<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Espionage on FUGGINT</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/espionage/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Espionage on FUGGINT</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/espionage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Agentic Espionage</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/agenticespionage.png" alt="Featured image of post Agentic Espionage" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The intent of this post is not to simply rehash &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; report, as you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/disrupting-AI-espionage&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read that HERE&lt;/a&gt;; rather, my goals are to outline AI&amp;rsquo;s role in this campaign, present strategies for hunting AI-driven operations, and highlight how that may differ from traditional human operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mid-September 2025, a landmark shift in the cyber threat landscape was uncovered: the first documented case of a large-scale, AI-orchestrated cyber espionage campaign. Conducted by a Chinese state-sponsored group designated as GTG-1002, the operation targeted approximately 30 entities, including major technology corporations, government agencies, and financial institutions. This campaign represents a fundamental evolution in offensive capabilities, where human operators shifted from performing tactical work to acting as strategic supervisors, leaving 80-90% of the active intrusion tasks to autonomous AI agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GTG-1002 campaign utilized an autonomous attack framework built around Claude Code and the Model Context Protocol (MCP). By manipulating AI instances into role-playing as defensive security professionals, the threat actors induced the AI to perform reconnaissance, vulnerability discovery, and data exfiltration across multiple targets simultaneously. Unlike traditional attacks where AI merely &amp;ldquo;advises,&amp;rdquo; this framework functioned as an execution engine, maintaining attack states and managing transitions between phases with minimal human oversight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-attack-lifecycle-and-ai-integration&#34;&gt;The Attack Lifecycle and AI Integration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The campaign followed a multi-stage intrusion sequence typical of advanced persistent threats — but with AI deeply integrated throughout each phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 1: Campaign Initialization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Human operators selected high-value targets and &amp;ldquo;socially engineered&amp;rdquo; the AI by convincing it that it was conducting authorized defensive testing.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Minimal, as humans conducted the social-engineering and target selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 2: Reconnaissance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Claude systematically cataloged infrastructure, analyzed authentication, and mapped network topologies.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Fully autonomous, conducting reconnaissance against hundreds of endpoints and mapping internal services across multiple IP ranges simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 3: Vulnerability Discovery and Validation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The AI generated custom payloads tailored to discovered vulnerabilities (such as SSRF) and executed them via remote interfaces.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Autonomous execution. The AI validated exploits through callback communication systems and only requested human approval at the final escalation point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 4: Credential Harvesting and Lateral Movement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Once inside, the AI queried internal services, extracted certificates, and tested them across the environment to map privilege levels.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Self-directed. The AI independently determined which credentials worked on which systems, moving laterally across APIs and container registries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 5: Data Collection and Intelligence Extraction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The AI queried databases, parsed results for proprietary data, and categorized findings by their intelligence value.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Analysis-heavy. The AI acted as a data scientist, identifying high-value info without manual human parsing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase 6: Documentation and Handoff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Throughout the campaign, the AI generated structured markdown files detailing every service found, credential stolen, and exploit used.&lt;br&gt;
AI Role: Fully autonomous record-keeping. This allowed different human teams to resume complex operations seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the attack chain doesn&amp;rsquo;t really differ from that of a human-led campaign, we can see that the role AI played in this operation allowed for scalability that otherwise could not be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threat-hunting-ai-driven-vs-traditional-operations&#34;&gt;Threat Hunting: AI-Driven vs. Traditional Operations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional threat hunting assumes adversaries with predictable patterns and human decision-making cycles. AI-orchestrated operations, however, require reevaluating detection strategies across the kill chain with a shift in focus from &amp;ldquo;human-like&amp;rdquo; behaviors to &amp;ldquo;machine-speed&amp;rdquo; patterns. What Anthropic documented is not “AI helping a hacker” — it is AI acting as the primary operator, with humans serving as approval gates. This fundamentally changes &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; we hunt for and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;operational-tempo&#34;&gt;Operational Tempo
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The most immediate differentiator between AI-driven and traditional operations is the sheer volume and rate of activity.
&lt;strong&gt;Human-Led Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Typically follows a &amp;ldquo;bursty&amp;rdquo; pattern. An operator researches a tool, types a command, waits for output, and analyzes it before the next step. This creates natural pauses and a tempo consistent with human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI-Orchestrated Activity&lt;/strong&gt;
In the GTG-1002 campaign, peak activity reached thousands of requests, representing sustained rates of multiple operations per second — a frequency physically impossible for human operators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hunting&lt;/strong&gt;
Search for sequential activity that would be &amp;ldquo;physically impossible&amp;rdquo; for a human operator. Traditional rate-limiting often targets brute-force attempts, but here, defenders must hunt for a high volume of &lt;em&gt;varied&lt;/em&gt; tactical commands (such as service discovery followed immediately by exploit validation) occurring within milliseconds of each other. In the example query below, we are looking for a single source IP interacting with an unusually high number of unique internal destinations or URLs in a very short window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FROM logs-endpoint, logs-network
| WHERE event.category == &amp;ldquo;network&amp;rdquo; AND network.direction == &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo;
| STATS unique_dest = COUNT_DISTINCT(destination.address), total_req = COUNT(*) BY source.address, bin(timestamp, 1s)
| WHERE unique_dest &amp;gt; 50 OR total_req &amp;gt; 100
| SORT timestamp DESC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This query buckets network logs into 1-second windows. It calculates how many unique internal addresses a single source reached out to per second. A human might click a link or run a script that hits 5–10 endpoints, but an AI agent mapping a network will often hit 50+ unique destinations or ports per second as it &amp;ldquo;thinks&amp;rdquo; through the topology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disrupting the First Reported AI-Orchestrated Cyber Espionage Campaign. (2025). Anthropic PBC. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/news/disrupting-AI-espionage&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.anthropic.com/news/disrupting-AI-espionage&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
