<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>FUGGINT</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
        <description>Recent content on FUGGINT</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Threat Hunting 101</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/threat-hunting-101/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/threat-hunting-101/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/post/threat-hunting-101/ThreatHunting101.png" alt="Featured image of post Threat Hunting 101" /&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;What better way to kick this blog off than by providing an overview on threat hunting. It&amp;rsquo;s been done a thousand times before, but threat hunting is a crucial, and often misunderstood, component of security. The purpose of this introductory post is to simply define some key aspects of threat hunting and provide a general process for the threat hunting workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern cybersecurity landscape, traditional defensive solutions such as firewalls, IDS/IPS, and EDR are essential but insufficient. Sophisticated adversaries are constantly developing new methods for bypassing such automated defenses. Thus enters threat hunting, a hypothesis-driven and proactive strategy for identifying sophisticated threats. Threat hunting has become a core capability for mature security teams, bridging the gap between traditional detection and proactive defense. Unlike alert-driven monitoring, threat hunting assumes that adversaries may already be present in an environment and focuses on identifying malicious activity that has evaded existing controls.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Principal Defensive Cyberspace Operator (DCO) Analyst with 7+ years experience as a cyber professional. My expertise lies in threat hunting, threat intelligence, and incident response. I created this blog to document various
efforts such as threat hunting strategies, timelining historical intrusions, and overviews of various APTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My career in cyber began in the Air Force where, as a Cyber Warfare Operator, I was assigned to a National Cyberspace Protection Team. During this time, I would engage in threat hunting operations both overseas and via state-side support to assist foreign mission partners in identifying and disrupting adversary activity. While separating from the Air Force, I participated in the DoD SkillBridge program, obtaining an internship position as an analyst on the Falcon Complete team at CrowdStrike. In this role, I responded to active intrusions and took remediation actions in the customer environment. After completing SkillBridge, I joined the OverWatch team as a threat hunter where I hunted eCrime and nation-state actors in both commercial and government environments. I am now back in the government sector as a contractor, currently supporting the US Army as a threat hunting SME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I possess CISSP, GCFA, CEH, and CompTIA Security+ certification. I have an MS in Cybersecurity from Georgia Tech and a BS in Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Links</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/links/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/links/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/page/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/page/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
