<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Threat Intelligence on FUGGINT</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/threat-intelligence/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Threat Intelligence on FUGGINT</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/threat-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Agentic Espionage</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/post/agenticespionage/agenticespionage.png" alt="Featured image of post Agentic Espionage" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What better way to kick this blog off than by providing an overview on threat hunting. It&amp;rsquo;s been done a thousand times before, but threat hunting is a crucial, and often misunderstood, component of security. The purpose of this introductory post is to simply define some key aspects of threat hunting and provide a general process for the threat hunting workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the modern cybersecurity landscape, traditional defensive solutions such as firewalls, IDS/IPS, and EDR are essential but insufficient. Sophisticated adversaries are constantly developing new methods for bypassing such automated defenses. Thus enters threat hunting, a hypothesis-driven and proactive strategy for identifying sophisticated threats. Threat hunting has become a core capability for mature security teams, bridging the gap between traditional detection and proactive defense. Unlike alert-driven monitoring, threat hunting assumes that adversaries may already be present in an environment and focuses on identifying malicious activity that has evaded existing controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-threat-hunting&#34;&gt;What is Threat Hunting?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At its core, threat hunting is a hypothesis-driven, proactive security activity aimed at identifying threats that bypass automated detections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Threat hunting differs from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SOC alert triage (reactive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident response (post-compromise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threat intelligence consumption (contextual)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, threat hunting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starts with an assumption of compromise/hypothesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverages telemetry across endpoints, identity, cloud, and network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focuses on behaviors, not just alerts - we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss indicators of attack vs indicators of compromise further down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-why-threat-hunting&#34;&gt;So Why Threat Hunting?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned above, traditional security solutions simply are not sufficient for disrupting sophisticated adversary activity. By leveraging threat hunting capabilities, an organization can proactively find hidden attackers and advanced threats that bypass automated defenses, thus reducing dwell time, identifying security gaps, and disrupting adversary activity.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Threat Intelligence 101</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/threat-intelligence-101/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/threat-intelligence-101/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/post/threat-intelligence-101/ThreatIntelligence101.png" alt="Featured image of post Threat Intelligence 101" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Threat Intelligence (TI) is the practice of collecting, analyzing, and operationalizing information about adversaries, their capabilities, infrastructure, and intent to inform security decision‑making. Where threat hunting is proactive detection inside your environment, threat intelligence provides the external context that helps you decide &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; to hunt for, &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it matters, and &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; attackers are likely to operate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mature threat intelligence program does not exist to produce reports for their own sake — it exists to reduce risk, improve detection, and enable faster, more confident response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-threat-intelligence&#34;&gt;What is Threat Intelligence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-it-is&#34;&gt;What It Is
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evidence‑based insight about adversaries, campaigns, tools, techniques, and infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contextualized analysis that supports prevention, detection, response, and strategic planning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intelligence that is actionable, timely, and relevant to your organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-it-is-not&#34;&gt;What It Is Not
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A raw feed of IPs, hashes, or domains with no context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A replacement for detection engineering, threat hunting, or incident response&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A one‑time project or a purely vendor‑driven capability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;threat-intelligence-lifecycle&#34;&gt;Threat Intelligence Lifecycle
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like threat hunting, threat intelligence follows a repeatable, structured lifecycle to ensure consistency and impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Planning and Direction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Intelligence analysts must first define &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; intelligence questions need answered. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which ransomware groups target organizations in our industry?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What cloud‑focused attack techniques are trending right now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which vulnerabilities are most likely to be exploited against us?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions can/should be driven by concerns such as business risks, threat model gaps, and detection/response priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Collection&lt;/strong&gt;
Once a question has been defined, data must be gathered from both internal and external sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SIEM and EDR telemetry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident response reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threat hunting findings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OSINT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commercial intel feeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vendor reports and advisories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government and ISAC sharing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Processing&lt;/strong&gt;
In this stage of the lifecycle analysts need to &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; the data by normalizing, enriching, and structuring. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsing indicators into structured formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enriching IPs and domains with ASN, geolocation, or reputation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mapping observed activity to MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;
Turn processed data into a &amp;ldquo;story.&amp;rdquo; This is where analysts identify patterns and provide context, answering questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happened?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why does it matter?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does this affect us specifically?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Dissemination&lt;/strong&gt;
Of course, none of this really matters until the right information is passed along to the right people. Depending on the content, intelligence reports need to be disseminated to the appropriate audience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executive briefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SOC-ready detection recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threat hunting leads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incident response playbooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Feedback and Refinement&lt;/strong&gt;
Reporting should be reviewed for usefulness, relevance, and impact, and then improved upon for the next cycle. Some key considerations include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did this intel change a decision?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did it improve detections or response?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was it timely and relevant?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
